This is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-radio.net
SE radio is brought to you by the ITE
computer society by it e software
magazine online at
computer.org/software.
[music]
Hey, this is Jeremy Jung for Software
Engineering Radio and today I'm talking
to Scott Hanselman. He's the vice
president of developer community at
Microsoft and I last spoke to Scott back
in 2021 where we discussed.NET. Scott,
welcome back to software engineering
radio.
>> Hey man, how are you?
>> Pretty good. Today we're going to talk
about all these AI assisted development
tools that are out there and I think
it's super overwhelming for a lot of our
listeners and for myself. So let's give
an overview of maybe the types of tools
you have experience with. I think maybe
we could start with just the chat bots,
the chat GPTs and the text box. Do you
go back and forth on?
>> I would even go farther back if I may.
>> Yeah.
>> And not to put too fine a point on it,
but let's go back to like 1975 cuz I was
thinking about this yesterday. I was
trying to explain this to my wife and
it's like when I started coding in like
8084, I went from assembler to C and
people would be like C, come on, that's
too high level, man. You got to get down
to the middle, right? You're like it's
going to rot your brain. C is going to
rot your brain. And then in the early
90s we got color and by that I mean we
got syntax highlighting and they're like
oh it's going to rot your brain and then
we got stack overflow and they were like
oh you're rot your brain and now we got
this. When we started thinking about AI
augmented coding it was next token
prediction. You type a for loop you hit
space and then it makes like ghost text
and suggests. So that's the first thing.
Then there was the chatbot. So just
right before the chatbot there was the
ghost text. you know, where it would
like interrupt you and they would have
like next token prediction within the
editor and some people really like that
because it's like oh I know what I'm
doing and then it's just going to
autocomplete. So it's like autocomplete
on steroids. Then people went into chat
GPT and started asking questions and
then they would copy paste not from
stack overflow they'd copy paste from
chatgpt then the agentic loop started
and that's where things got interesting
and if you really want to sound smart in
meetings just say agentic as many times
as possible and agentic loop sounds even
smarter but the idea was that why am I
copy pasting this code from chat GPT
when I could just let the agent the LLM
run build look at the text see a warning
fix the warning and then loop and that's
when we started getting into things like
GitHub copi and gemini and AMP and open
code and claude and all of those kind of
things where it's LLM sees some tokens
gets the result makes a judgment and it
I call it the ambiguity loop cuz this is
the thing about programming versus LLM
programming programming is not ambiguous
it runs exactly as you wrote it and if
there's a bug it's your fault and if you
want a for loop you write the for loop,
you do it in bash or powershell or
whatever and it does the thing. But an
ambiguity loop is like, yeah, I don't
really know like things could happen.
And we fool ourselves into thinking like
regular expressions and stuff handle
ambiguity. But if you imagine this kind
of slider bar of ambiguity between I'm
parsing this binary and it's going to
work this way and here's the way that
the bytes are packed versus the like I
don't know man, it's unstructured data.
What are you going to do? LLMs are
really good at ambiguity. Turns out the
toil part of programming is really
ambiguous. Like I'm writing this bot on
this other machine over here. I'm
running what's called a Ralph loop that
we'll talk about later. And it's bumping
into all kinds of little weird problems.
And those little weird problems are just
crap that I would have to go and Google
or look on Stack Overflow. It's just
ambiguity. So I'm running not a Ralph
loop, but an ambiguity loop that's like
working that out because that's not the
fun part of programming. The fun part of
programming is like building stuff. So I
think that these agents and why people
are freaking out about them is because
it's that same feeling that we got when
Stack Overflow happened. We're like,
"Oh, programming's over or when when I
got syntax highlighting and I was like,
I don't have to do anything now. The all
the text is in color." Does that make
sense? That's how I contextualize it
across a historical context. Yeah. I
think that's good to bring it back to
the syntax highlighting and the
autocomplete because I think nowadays
it's very uncontroversial, right? people
for the most part will accept like, oh,
the syntax highlighting is there. It
helps me
>> good way to put point out what I'm
looking for. The autocomplete, I can
quickly see is the suggestion something
I want, yes or no. I think for the most
part, people are on board. And I think
this ambiguity loop you're talking about
is maybe a little bit I think people
have more mixed feelings about is
because of that what you're describing
where it's like this slot machine,
right? Like maybe it'll give you a good
answer, maybe it won't.
>> Yes. And here's a really great I had
this internal conversation with this guy
like we're on teams and this is an
internal guy and he was so excited
because he did a oneshot. A oneshot is
when you type one prompt and then
software pops out. He did a oneshot and
he cloned Minecraft and there's this
thing that I think it's called there's a
paper I think it's like project unicorn
or something like that where like open
AI cloned Minecraft. But forget about
that result for a second and think about
the simple semantics of typing in a
prompt. Make me a clone of Minecraft
that runs in the browser using 3JS.
Which word in that sentence is doing the
heavy lifting, the heavy semantic
lifting? There's Minecraft and there's
3JS because you're steering it and
saying use 3JS versus using Babel versus
using whatever. But in that sentence,
make me a clone means a copy of
Minecraft means a lot. The word
Minecraft semantically is effectively a
50page spec. So I was trying to tell the
guy, "Dude, that word is doing literally
all the lifting." Try explaining to it
to give you a clone of Minecraft, except
you don't get to use the word Minecraft,
right? And now that would be effectively
impossible. Now you go from, "Oh my
gosh, I did a oneshot of Minecraft to
this is a hot mess and I really need to
be specific." and you're going to get
like you said a roll of the dice. So we
need to ask ourselves when we are making
these ambiguity loops. What is the job
of the programmer? Well, it's to be
specific because it's all about
expressing your intent and making your
intent understood. And I'm sure we would
have loved in the '60s '7s and ' 80s to
like just talk to the thing, but it
wasn't specific enough. So we needed to
be so specific that I'm like put that
electron in that register and we're
going to use assembly to do it. And now
suddenly I can say hey computer what's
my blood sugar and it knows to go into a
REST API to get the tokens to go up to
my database to bring all that kind
of stuff down cuz suddenly the Lego
pieces are high enough and the stack is
deep enough that I can get what I want.
And it might try it in Python one day.
It might try it in JavaScript one day.
The result is I get to know what my
blood sugar is because a REST API is
called. But that ambiguity loop
shouldn't be something that we should
take for granted because it's not going
to work every time. And that's why I
think it's interesting to use the
ambiguity loop to get me specific
software that runs absolutely reliably
because talking to chatbt or talking to
Claude, that's not a scripting language,
right? It's effectively a pros compiler
and that's different. So, I'm using it
to make grounded scripts that I then run
rather than just yapping at the thing
and pretending that it's bash files.
>> In some ways, it's like that shift you
were talking about earlier where you
went from writing assembly or machine
code to writing compiled languages
compiled down to that. And then we got
to higher level languages like
JavaScript. And then now we're one level
even before that. We have our English
pros that's helping us compile or
generate the high level language.
>> You know how people use like Lua or C
and they build it into like Unity apps,
right? And it's like that's the
scripting language for their game. That
makes sense to me. To embed an LLM would
be to embed ambiguity which they think,
oh yeah, look, the NPCs are going to be
able to do stuff. But now they could do
anything. They could say dumb stuff.
They could go off the rails and the game
could completely do something that you
don't want it to do. That's what we
don't want to do. We don't want to push
out slop because rolling the dice is not
software engineering.
>> And I think maybe another important
point is with that example where you
said somebody tried to oneshot let's
write Minecraft, right? My guess is that
the end result was not actually
Minecraft. It was probably something
that resembled it a little bit. But
>> yeah, I wish I could show you. It's
actually, to be clear, it's super
impressive. It's a full Voxil world. It
generates the voxels. It runs in the
browser. The textures are all there.
There's no crafting in mine, but you've
got an inventory. It's Minecraft if you
woke up from a dream and you're just
like, "Oh, I had a dream. I was in
Minecraft." So, it's maybe like 60% of
Minecraft. And that's pretty cool. But
again, the spec lives entirely in the
word Minecraft. Because if you said,
"Make me a clone of fufu and fufu isn't
a thing," you're going to just roll the
dice and it's going to go insane. That's
why it's not a reasonable demo to say,
"Make me a Space Invaders. Make me a
Pac-Man. Make me a Donkey Kong." Because
those words do all the heavy lifting.
>> I feel like some of the higher levels
people who are running these businesses,
CEOs, and things like that, they have
this vision that I'm going to be able to
ask this rather ambiguous thing and get
a complete product. But to me, it feels
like we're not actually there.
>> So, an example that I really like to use
and then may I ask, do you have a car
and do you drive?
>> I do. Yeah.
>> Okay. Do you drive stick or do you drive
automatic?
>> Automatic.
>> Do you know how to drive stick?
>> I don't know it well enough to
comfortably do it.
>> Okay. Do you feel that it is a personal
failing that you don't know how to drive
stick?
>> I do not.
>> Okay. So, take everything that we just
talked about and now apply it to
programming, right? Like I could do
assembler, but I couldn't do it without
googling anymore. Do I feel bad about
that? No. Could I drive it in an
emergency? Yes. Could you drive someone
to the hospital and stick? Yes. You
could probably make it happen if you
were in a pinch. Here's the question,
though. What if you answered just now,
"I don't have a car. I only know how to
Uber." Then your relationship to the
vehicle fundamentally changes. And if
the vehicle breaks, you're going to get
out of that car. You're going to leave
that poor gentleman there. He's going to
have to fix that car. He's going to have
to repair it. Oil change and tires. And
you're just going to get in another Uber
and fly away. But how deep is the stack
for you to simply move your body from
point A to point B? And you have no
control over how the guy is going to get
you there. So I think that there is
value in driving stick occasionally
trying to get somewhere without a GPS
because then the ambiguity has to be and
the responsibility is on you. The honest
is on you while right now the idea like
hey send a stranger in a car with candy
to pick me up and I just like lean back.
That's the same thing asking an Uber to
send you somewhere and asking Claude
code or GitHub co-pilot to make
something for you with no specificity.
You're lucky. I I hope you get to the
airport. Good luck. You know what I
mean?
>> Well, I suppose in that example, the
Uber or the Lyft, you're giving an
address most likely and it's sort of
this welldefined problem of I need to
get this person to the airport or I need
to get this person of the end,
>> right? And I feel like that's a little
different than me saying telling an LLM,
please build me a web browser or build
me Minecraft.
>> That's fair. I think an example would
be, "Hey Uber, take me to the airport."
>> Without specifying which one
>> without specifying and there's no ask
user question.
>> I guess your point maybe is that it's
somewhat unrealistic to say something so
vague and not expect there to be a back
and forth to be clarifying questions,
that kind of thing.
>> Exactly. And I'm sure you've been in an
Uber and you've told them, "Hey, take
the 405." Because you were steering
them.
>> You're not driving the car, but you
steered. And that's why we're finding
steering in these CLI coding agents so
delightful where it's like you're 90% in
the direction I need you to go. Just get
off on this exit. Those little moments
matter. Specificity matters. I'll give
you another example. My son is 18 and he
has a depot. So he sells like vintage
clothing on depot which is like a
marketplace for people to sell clothing.
But he ships on a website called pirate
ship. He doesn't use the beat depot
built-in shipping. So, I had this vision
to make it so he didn't have to copy
paste stuff back and forth. And I
thought I was going to do it with like
Playright and I was going to automate
browsers and I was going to build a
whole like dashboard for him to do
shipping. And I was basically using the
co-pilot as a rubber duck. I was talking
back and forth to it. I was talking to
myself in the mirror. I'm not actually
talking to an entity. I'm talking to
myself. And in the brainstorming, just
as if I called you and brainstormed, we
realized that, oh, I don't want to write
a playwright extension. I want a browser
extension. So, I wrote a browser toolbar
for him and I wouldn't have come up with
that. I would have gone all the way down
Playright automation and been wrong
because of my own biases if I hadn't
brainstormed. And a little bit of the
ambiguity loop popped up and said, "Have
you thought about a browser extension?"
And it clicked and then I went
immediately. It's like, "Hey, take me to
JFK. You know, EWR has a direct flight.
Have you thought about that? You're
right. Let's do it." And that back and
forth as well as having a lot of
experience and understanding the power
of a browser extension turned out to be
a really great experience. And now he's
got oneclick shipping for his little
business.
>> Very cool. I have people ask me
sometimes, is it still worth learning
how to code? Is it still worth learning
all the specificity of HTTP or how the
browser works or databases? And I think
what you're maybe implying is that
having at least some background in these
things will help guide you when you're
asking these questions, when you're
trying to come to a solution. If you
don't have that background, you might
not get there.
>> I acknowledge my position in history, my
age, where I grew up. I speak English.
I'm a white guy on the West Coast. Like
all those kind of things are the context
in which I came up. I came up in a very
interesting time in the '8s programming.
So, I don't want to sound like old man
who shakes fist at Cloud. Hey, bro. Why
are you gatekeeping stuff, right? But I
see people saying, "Hey man, I just vibe
the world's greatest new SAS. Check it
out." And they tweet local host 3000.
And it's just like, right? So, like, do
you buy your furniture at IKEA? I do.
Could you cut a board? Did you take
probably wood shop? Yeah. Would you
build your own furniture? No. But you
have an appreciation for building IKEA
stuff. I think that's why IKEA makes you
build it so that you don't feel like it
just appeared in your house. It can't
just like spawn up like Billy shelves.
So yes, while recognizing that it might
sound like, hey, this old guy wants me
to write everything in assembler. Yes,
yes, yes. Appreciating that oil changes
are a thing, DevOps is a thing, build
loops are a thing, and quality matters.
So I would argue that it's not the death
of software engineering, it's the death
of toil and the only thing that matters
now is taste and judgment.
>> So where do you think that that balance
is? What do you think people should be
learning where they can use these tools
effectively and they can still be
building quality?
>> I think and by the way when I retire I'm
going to go and teach high school
computer science. That's my plan. I've
got it all lined up and I was a
professor before and I'll be a professor
again. I don't think there's enough
computer science history and I don't
think there's enough basics. I don't
think anyone learned HTTP in college,
right? They just kind of sat down, they
did compilers, they learned Lex and Yak,
and then suddenly you're learning OSS
and then you're writing apps. But you
pick up HTTP and DNS and stuff like
that. Maybe like I took a 400 level TCP
IP class, but as a general rule, you're
not spending a lot of time learning how
to do Kubernetes in school. I think
HTTP, DNS,NATS,
like that's all bread and butter. That's
sociology, right? Like why do you learn
about world history so you can go and be
like a corporate drone? You learn
because it makes you a whole full
person. So there is someone right now
vibe of coding their bachelor's degree
in software engineering. And I love that
for them. But they're going to get
nailed just as people who don't learn
about sociology and history and
psychology are going to get nailed. The
Dunning Krueger effect is a real thing.
Hypothetically, when you're teaching
your computer science class, what would
you tell your students in terms of using
these AI assisted tools? I would say it
is a funny two-faced thing because it is
a senior engineer with infinite
patience, but it is a junior engineer
with infinite energy. And the role that
the LLM chooses depends on how you're
coming at it. If I come at it as a net
engineer and I'm competent in C, then it
is a junior engineer with infinite
energy and I need to point it exactly
and I tell it what I want and it does
the thing. But if I come at it as a
Python developer of which I am a novice
or a medium, then it's more senior than
I am. So I would be less likely to
disagree if it makes a recommendation,
right? So if it does something innet
like no, don't use that, use this. I
will say no, we're going to JFK. Trust
me, this is how we're getting there. But
if I've never been to that country, I've
never been to that state, I don't know
which airport's the better, I'm going to
take the advice of the Uber driver. But
it's the same LLM. It's the same model.
And if you come at it with that sense of
like, no, I know what I'm doing. Strong
opinions weekly held, you're going to
have a much better experience.
Additionally, the opening prompts
matter, and I think that there's room
for learning prompts. So, if I were
teaching the class, I would include a
markdown file and skills that would
force the user to like, oh, you just
tried to vibe your entire final. Here's
some multiple choice questions. Here's
an exercise for the reader. I'm not
going to let them just oneshotting your
computer science file. You're doing
yourself a disservice. I think if you do
that,
>> yeah, that's an interesting point about
how the way you interact with the LLM is
so different when you know the domain or
you know the language well. And I wonder
if in your opinion if it's let's say you
don't know it well. Are you in a sense
sort of faded to get a result that's
maybe not as good like because you
didn't have that background because you
couldn't steer it? If you don't
understand why it did a thing then I
would not feel comfortable shipping it.
And that's where I think the limit is.
Like I'm doing a bunch of Python stuff
and I think I'm maybe a four out of 10
or five out of 10, but I know how their
type system works versus TypeScript
versus whatever. So I'm asking generic
computer science questions like what's
the Python equivalent of a llinter? Do I
have enough guards for my exceptions?
Like that's not Python questions. That's
just quality. That's just taste. And
I'll say I'll challenge its assumptions.
It's like I built a blood sugar
management system in Python a couple of
days ago and I've asked it like should
this be TypeScript and I said make me a
pros and cons table about moving this to
TypeScript and it was like no I think
Python works great and we kept it at
Python but then I had another thing that
I was doing in C and it was on .NET
framework and I thought it would just be
fine on .NET framework. I said no no we
should move to .NET 10. Here's 10
reasons why and it's a back and forth. I
think too many people are trying to vibe
code stuff in two or three shots while
I'm doing stuff in 50 or 60 and having
ongoing conversations. Like I'm
gesturing right here. People can't see
to my terminal which has 13 tabs open
and they're all doing something right
now. And I use Copilot CLI which is like
cloud code. It's an agent loop and it
has infinite sessions. So it has this
idea of like the context of like how
long it can think about stuff doesn't
exist in copilot CLI. So I can just go
d-res and pick up stuff I worked on a
week ago and it's like a hibernation. I
just hibernated the agent. I brought it
back. So it's remembering all the stuff
and all the decisions I've been making
on and I'll say stuff like revisit our
conversation from a week ago. Do you
still think that's true? Go and look at
this poll request. Go and look at this
Stack Overflow. Go and look at this new
tweet that someone that Simon Willis
said. And given that new context, what
do you think? So I'm constantly
challenging it. And it's almost like
I've got 13 engineers that are either
working full-time or they're just asleep
and I wake them up and I ask them a
question and then I go off and I do my
thing. And it's really been like I feel
like an engineering manager with a lot
of really cool little junior engineers
with so much energy.
>> And for someone who isn't super familiar
with the domain or with the language
they're working in, how do you verify
the assertions that the LLM is making?
>> I love that. I love that. So because I'm
not an expert in Python, but I wrote my
blood sugar management system in Python.
However, I am an expert in type 1
diabetes. So I thought to myself, how
can I verify that this is valid, but I
don't know the language and it's what I
call fear-based development, right? It's
FDD, fear-driven development. I don't
want to screw this thing up. It's my
blood sugar. And in the words of Brian
Lyles, test all theing time, right?
Always. So, how many tests do I need
before I don't feel scared? In this one
here, it ended up being 270. That's just
a number, but like I needed about 70%
code coverage across almost 300 tests
and it's on real data and it works. So,
that that's CI/CD and it runs in GitHub
actions and it runs locally. It does
nothing until it tests. And I would
again argue that that's about software
engineering, not about Python. So, as
long as there's a test framework and a
loop and that loop is verifiable, that's
what's important because everyone's
excited about like Ralph loops, which we
should talk about at some point. Ralph
loops are great, but like if you have a
million monkeys and they're typing in a
million typewriters and you're hoping
that they're going to type Shakespeare,
if you don't have a test that validates
the Shakespeare, then you're just
wasting monkeys and wasting typewriters.
>> And these tests, are you generally
writing them yourself or is this
something that the LLM is also writing?
So I will write four or five tests
myself. Then I'll tell the LM to write
me other tests on the boring stuff like
edge cases and then because we know that
in software engineering the top three
issues in software engineering is naming
stuff and off by one errors. So that is
the things I watch for. I know that it's
edge cases. So I'll write a test. I'll
have it make me 10 more and then I'll
look for all the edge cases. And yes,
it's true that I haven't deeply
validated them. And it is true that
depending on the model you use, it'll
comment tests out. It'll hide stuff from
you. It'll pretend. It'll gaslight you
into thinking the tests work. And this
is why it's so important that you
understand, not you, but one understand
that you are shipping this code. Like I
always think it's funny when someone
puts something up in the cloud and the
cloud goes down and then they're mad at
the cloud provider. Like I get that
you're mad at the cloud provider, but
like whose responsibility is it for that
app? It's your responsibility. If you
felt that strongly, you should have had
it in two cloud providers, right? So if
this thing fails, it's me. It's 100% me.
I'm not going to blame Copilot or Claude
or whoever wrote that code. That's why
when you check stuff in to GitHub, it
says on behalf of if I did something and
my proxy did it for me, it's the buck
stops here. So if this were production,
production, production, I would go and
double check it. And that's why like for
example, the co-pilot CLI team, it's
like seven or eight engineers and
they're doing like 200 PRs a week. It's
crazy. They're spending more time now
reviewing than they are writing code,
but they will not ship slop. And if you
look at another way, I'm sorry I'm
talking so much, but another way to
think about it is when open source
started and the open source supply chain
started having all this flood of open
source software. How do we deal with
this? Code came from somewhere into the
machine. Doesn't matter whether Jeremy
wrote it or whether some kid wrote it
and it got in via PR or whether an LLM
code. It has got to go through the same
verification loops, the same security
loops, the same testing loops, the same
provenence loops, the same governance.
That makes sense to me. I mean something
that you sometimes hear people say with
all these tools the agents the ability
to generate code they're saying well I
am generating so much I just don't have
time or I just don't need to verify the
output and it sounds like in your case
you're saying no ultimately even though
these tools are generating it it still
comes down to you need to review it
because otherwise you don't know what's
going on if I don't have time then what
are you making, right? The point is to
make a thing and ship a thing that
you're proud of. So then we got to go,
we got to go. Well, then you don't care.
You don't care about your customers.
Like you have to understand the
semantics or what are you even doing? I
just reject that. Now that said, there
is this rise of toy fun personal apps.
Like using computer science history to
put this in context, we're having a
geocities moment, right? Where
everyone's just making stuff. There's
this wonderful friend of mine on TikTok
named Rodney Norman. He's a comedian.
He's got crazy white hair like Professor
Brown and he's got a big long beard and
he pops up on my for you page and he
says, "You know, you can just make
stuff. You can just do stuff now."
That's what it feels like. I got a
rocket ship strapped to my back and I'm
just making stuff. That doesn't mean I'm
going to go and plug Stripe into it and
start taking money for it and like
taking people's money and real blood
sugar. So, you see the difference? If
you're shipping this, you better care.
If you're just playing, Yeah. play.
>> Yeah. I mean, colloquially, right,
people are saying, "I vibecoded this."
>> I don't say that anymore. [laughter]
If I vibe coded it, I don't care. You
either are a vibe coder or you're an AI
augmented software engineer. AI
augmented software engineer doesn't have
good mouth feel. But like, bro, it's
just vibes. No, I'm not vibing into
production. That's not happening. Yeah.
And I I think to what people may run
into is whatever they build may look
like it works initially, but there may
be architectural problems that make it
difficult to change. There could be more
severe flaws that you just can't find
because you don't know enough about
what's happening.
>> You don't know what you don't know. And
the first database migration or like the
first scale issue and you're like, "Oh,
we made a decision." Well, actually, we
didn't make a decision. the ambiguity
loop punted on a decision and now we're
painted into a corner, an architectural
corner.
>> So I think one of the things you
mentioned is when you work on a project,
it sounds like you have this plan or you
have a lot of context that you're
providing to the model to start off. Can
you kind of walk through what are the
kinds of things that you're saying? like
are you asking for specific architecture
patterns, languages, ways to test, that
kind of thing?
>> Trying to think of an example. I'm
looking at my tabs that are working
right here. Okay, here's one. So,
there's an application that is 20 years
old. It's called Windows Live Writer.
It's a blogging tool and we Microsoft
released it in like 2006 and then we
open sourced it later and it's a mix of
C++ car the ribbon control from office
the internet explorer like the actual
typing the blog post is actually a comm
object from internet explorer and it
works but it's janky and it needs to be
modernized so it's like 20-year-old
software that's an interesting technical
problem because it's a brownfield pile
of stuff but I have a vision that we
could get that running on net 10 which
didn't exist with chromium or web view 2
instead of trident which is the internet
explorer thing we could update the
ribbon control I can see you're nodding
the spec is already in your head so then
the question is how specific do you
express that intent to something like
this and the arguably there's kind of
two ways to do it there's the persistent
loop the Ralph loop which is just like
do this make no mistakes right that's
just monkeys slapping but verifiable
loops with persistence is really
interesting. So, how do you verify that
it works? What's changed contextually
since this thing came out 4K monitors
happened? That wasn't a thing 20 years
ago. Multiple DPI across multiple
monitors. So, like I know that that's a
thing. So, I put that in the spec.net is
crossplatform, but this is a Windows
app. So, I'm not trying to get this
thing to run crossplatform. So, that
goes in the spec. It's C++ and it uses
COM, but I don't really need COM anymore
for this because I'm going to be
switching over to Chromium. So, I'll
make a COM to JavaScript bridge. Those
little moments make that loop, which I
could have probably pointed a loop at it
and it would fix it at some point, but
it saves time. These are all these
little architectural shortcuts where I'm
anticipating that this is important or
that's important. It found a reference
to MySpace cuz it had like an insert
MySpace link. So, like I said, go
through the thing. If there's plugins
for dead services, mark them as to-do,
keep track in the to-do of all the
things that you've stubbed out, etc.,
etc., etc. I think I ended up basically
dictating to the thing about a 2 and 1/2
page spec. And I think we looped, I want
to say 20 times and it's running like it
freaking works. I'd say it's probably 70
80% done. And then now people are doing
PRs against it and we've revitalized
this 20-year-old application. The
question is, could we have done it by
just saying, "Get this running on
Windows." Again, I think that the
reinforcement that we would give an LLM
to do that would be artificial because
it doesn't know what success looks like.
It might just say, "Oh, I got it
running, but like, did you get it
running? Did you post a blog post? Did
the blog post work? Did you edit the
blog post?" So, you got to think like a
tester. Remember back in the day when
like software testers were like, "That
was an actual job." It's a job again. So
I feel like I'm talking to this engineer
that's overseas or outsourced or
insourced and they're throwing code at
me and I'm validating that code. So I
make a plan that's about 80% of a plan
and I tell it if you have questions ask
if you're making architectural decision
ask. And if there's a lack of clarity or
the loop is unclear then I will come up
with a solution. Another example
actually because it's a Windows app
how's it going to validate? Does it take
a screenshot? Does it like do debug got
here debugging? Does it do interactive
debugging? Those are all interesting
things that are happening right now as
well because it can't see unless it's
multimodal like something like like
copilot CLI. I told it to take
screenshots and compare it to the other
one and see how close it was. So there's
anything you can do to make the plan
clearer and make the loop tighter will
cause it to be more successful. And when
you refer to these loops, I'm assuming a
loop is the model attempting to write
the code to accomplish what you asked
for. Is it automatically
looping on itself and it keeps trying or
is it where it's prompting you and going
like, "Okay, I gave my first try. Time
for you to review."
>> That's a great question. So with this
particular application which is trying
to bring back an old Windows app, it
would get it to compile and think that
was success. So I'm like, no, running it
is success. So then it gets it running,
it looks at the process tree and says,
look, it has a PID success. I'm like,
no, it has to look good. Oh, okay. Well
then, and then you can kind of start
upleveling. And then I realized I was
running this app called debug view,
which is effectively like the Windows
debug spew kind of thing. And I was
selecting the the got here debugging the
debug. guidelines and pasting it back
in. And after the third or fourth time,
I'm like, it can run it. It then asks
me, what do you see? It literally would,
what do you see in the debug view? And I
would copy paste it. I'm like, this is
stupid. So then we made debug view an
MCP server. Now I'm out of the loop. So
I actually got myself out of the loop.
So now it can compile, run, see the log,
kill the PID, build, and then the inner
loop becomes simpler. So then I said,
"Let me know and stop the loop when you
have questions or you think you're
done." And that's what's so kind of
exciting about these loops is if they're
clear and success is clear and
verifiable, you can do really amazing
stuff.
>> So it sounds like as a part of your
instructions, you're also giving it the
tools. You're telling it how it should
verify whether it actually did the
thing. So, like I'm making a Windows
Clawbot now moltbot Windows tray
application and it declared success just
right before we got on the call and it's
like yeah it's working it's great and I
looked at the tray and it says
connecting and it's not connecting at
all right it's completely and I'm like
no this isn't working and it's like no
no it's working I can see it's working
look and it shows me all the it's very
excited it's like oh and it's giving me
rocket ships and an emoji it's super
excited that everything is is working
great and then I realized that the UI is
done but the underlying stuff is not
done. So I need to separate the UI from
the business logic build the core which
is much easier with these loops. So then
once I get it talking to the API so it
was my own mistake to tell it you know
build this and I went UI down that was
foolish of me that was it was my own
enthusiasm that that nailed me. So now
I'm going to go and refactor it, pull
out the core, build the Windows front
end to the thing, get it connecting, and
then layer that UI on top of that
because that's way more verifiable. I
think it's a common experience with
people who use these tools that there
are times when they're in a loop or
they're trying to come to a solution and
each time they try it's just not what
you wanted or it's it's saying it fixed
it, but it really didn't. And are there
specific strategies you have for I guess
one recognizing you're caught in this
loop. It's not going to get out
>> and how do you break it out of that that
cycle?
>> For me, it's always been that it is
confused about what success looks like.
You have to remember that an intern or a
enthusiastic early in career engineer is
very excited to be at the company. I'm
so happy to be working with you Jeremy.
I'm going to do whatever it takes. lie,
cheat, steal, comment out tests in order
to make sure that you don't fire me.
These are reinforcement learned large
language models that are very very
excited to be here. And as such, just
like you know, the devil wears Prada,
the the interactions that they're going
to have with a salty old engineer like
me are going to be very interesting.
Like I guess I'm Merryill Streep in this
analogy. So I need to be very specific.
Okay, Jeremy, I need you to do this. I
need you to do it nicely. I want a half
double decaffeinated half cap with a
twist of lemon, not two twists. You know
what I mean? So, you need to be a little
bit crisp with it. If you can give it
test data, if you can give it verifiable
test data, if you can say build a
harness, if it doesn't know what success
is, it will make up success, declare
success, and then if you're not whatever
enough, senior enough, awake enough to
declare success and agree with it, then
you're going to get nailed.
>> Yeah. And in the example you gave
before, you had to tell it specifically
to use this debug view tool and give it
that tool through the MCP server. Yeah.
>> How would it know, right? You got to
tell it that you have these tools
available. It's going to take a regular
screwdriver and keep poking it into a
Phillips screwdriver thing. It's like,
you got a Phillips right there, bro. Oh,
you're absolutely right. I actually I
can't show you because we're on a audio
podcast, but literally yesterday I
forgot that I had a whole test harness
for my blood sugar thing and I had like
another 100 tests that I hadn't told it
about and it was frustrated about
something and I was like oh you know go
into this folder I've got these tests
and it literally said this is gold thank
you so much now I see you know and then
I was another totally unrelated thing I
was building a front end for for
Microsoft loop cuz I wanted to like loop
is like notion and I was building an API
for it And then I found API
documentation. I just pasted in here's
the URL for the documentation. And I was
like, ah, now I have a plan. So it's
just like giving it like a little breath
of fresh air and it's like ah and now
I'm re-energized. That's what these
these loops require. Ambiguity loops
require specificity. That's what we are
supposed to provide as software
engineers.
>> And as you have these longer loops or
conversations, one of the things about
these tools is they have a context. And
that context is only so large. And I I
wonder if you ever run into the issue of
I believe they call it context
compaction where eventually the model
has to kind of get rid of some of the
context that you had before and if you
run into that and how you deal with
that.
>> Yeah. So I just put in context here. I'm
73% into a 200,000 token context window.
That is often a thing in these loops
where it's it's talking to you and it's
talking then it kind of goes, huh? What?
Oh, I don't remember, bro. What? And
that's because it just compacted
everything, summarized it, and it
doesn't remember an hour ago. That
happens a lot on these tools. It happens
less so with the infinite sessions that
GitHub Copilot CLI has because it does
very, very active management of that
window, but I've also with any tool
found it to be very helpful to keep
telling it to save stuff. And I don't
like to anthropomorphize these things.
They're not people. But I have a context
window and I also have a remarkable e-
in thing and I sync to paper like tell
it to write stuff down as if it is a
person. So this big loop that I'm
running on the clawbot over here I said
every time you achieve something write
it down. And if you look at things like
Steve Yagi's beads which is basically
like a git focused to-do list that's
distributed across multiple agents that
are working on a swarm of problems. If
everyone can agree on a ledger of the
things that we're working on, those
context windows matter less because if
it wakes up, it's going to go and say,
"What? What am I doing? What was I
working on?" Just like the movie
Momento, when he forgets stuff, he
tattoos it all over his body. He wakes
up in the morning, he doesn't know who
he is, and he gets caught up by looking
in the mirror and seeing all the
tattoos. So, anytime anything
interesting happens in his life, he
tattoos it on himself to catch himself
up. Do you ever end find yourself doing
that manually where you yourself know
what the context should be and you just
go here you go like this is remember all
this or yeah so context window
management is not something I have been
actively doing with the copilot CLI
because of the sessions feature but I
still think it has a huge amount of
value because it's not about their
context it's about your context when you
Jeremy inherit the code later like for
example DPI we were having a dots per
inch issue with the open livewriter and
it was complicated [snorts]
Like I spent a day messing around with
DPI cuz multi DPI multiple monitors is
complicated. So I said write down
everything that we've learned so that no
one has to ever deal with this again.
and it made [clears throat] like a 2meg,
you know, markdown file like it
effectively wrote a chapter of a book
about nuance and I'm running the
claudebot now maltbot on Windows under
WSL and you know every once in a while a
Windows ism will come in and I said
regularly check for Windows isms and
remember it so that you never hit it
again and that's not thinking about the
larger context window that's just like
put a post-it note on your monitor to
remind you of this and with any project
I'll end up having 10 or 15 of those
that are secondary to the main plan. The
main plan could be in in something like
beads or it could be in GitHub actions
or it could be a markdown file with
checkboxes and the main plan and these
additional notes that you provide. Is
there a way that consistently works
across whether it's GitHub Copilot or
it's Cloud Code or Gemini CLI? Is is
there like a hey this is the markdown
file you put it into and all these
things will understand it.
>> They're all fighting right now about
what the thing will be called you know
like there's agents.mmd and there's
skills.mmd and like you know how there's
like a robots.ext which is like the
thing that your website puts up in order
to tell robots what to do and then
there's vlm.ext
which is literally a text file you put
on your website in order to like tell
openai or whoever is scraping your
website what to do about it. If you have
an agents.md, it's like a readme for
agents and then within that I'll say
there is a docs folder and within that
docs folder here are the main subsystems
and you're effectively building
architectural context and then if it
finds itself doing a thing then it will
go and refer to the documentation. So I
taught the claudebot about my blood
sugar which is unique to me. Anytime I
mention anything blood sugar related it
doesn't have to hold it in context. It
just has to know, oh, there's a post-it
note with the details that I need to
know, and then it pages it in, does the
thing, and then it pages out.
>> Something you mentioned earlier was you
were referring to this Ralph loop. What
What is that?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, Ralph loops are funny.
So, Ralph Wiggums is a character on The
Simpsons and he is a extremely naive and
extremely persistent funny little man.
What we admire about Ralph is that he is
persistent and he will never give up and
it is designed for these continuous
autonomous development cycles and Ralph
Wigum the concept was came up with a
gentleman named Jeffrey Huntley and he's
basically trying to do less and this is
a thing that I think we need to
acknowledge as programmers that we are
ultimately very lazy so if it can be
automated that's a good thing so he's
like why am I doing this work let Ralph
let Ralph do it so the Ralph loop kind
of embodies the spirit of this little
character on the Simpsons, which is I'm
going to stubbornly iterate. I'm going
to fail, but I'm never going to give up
until it succeeds. So, a really great
example of a Ralph loop is not
necessarily like the tech journalists
will say, "Oh, you can just point it at
some software and it'll clone it and it
will make like a Minecraft clone. It's
not going to be real, right?" But David
Fowler, distinguished engineer innet,
had a really interesting problem where
he had 400 issues in his GitHub repo for
an application and it didn't have good
reproductions of the bugs. And that's
just one of those things. It's just
technical debt and it we don't know if
they're bugs. It could be good bugs. We
don't know. So he made a Ralph loop that
said spin through all 400 of these
issues and reproduce them. If you get a
good reproduction, keep track of that
reproduction, then add that context to
the issue. That is the very definition
of toil. And like what better thing than
a Ralph loop to do that? And I think it
came up with something like 384 good
solid repros. Right now the big problem
with a Ralph loop is that it doesn't
have like a task tracker. So that's
where things get interesting. If you
have a task list and Ralph can then keep
track and understand what success looks
like, then you're going to have a great
experience with it. So, I will do
interactive work during the day and then
as I get towards the night, I'll be
like, "Okay, what's a loop that it could
work on overnight because I want to wake
up in the morning and have something
successful happen." It sounds wasteful,
but it's like shockingly cheap. You
know, I'm a bit of an AI vegan. I don't
do images and I don't do video, but next
token prediction is becoming extremely
inexpensive and you could run a loop all
night long and it might cost you like
two bucks. So if you have a problem that
is Ralph loopshaped
it can be an extremely powerful tool. I
think though that people sometimes think
that it is the only thing or they'll
take like vibe coding is fun to say and
now Ralph loop is fun to say but it's
just another technique. It's another
tool like like CI/CD
>> and is this where people have built this
I don't know what you would call it this
harness that is going to manage and run
the loop. Well, so Jeffrey Huntley calls
it a while bash loop. So it's just like
while true, you know, and the concept is
very simple. It reprompts your agent a
set number of times with the same
prompt. And we mentioned before that
it's an ambiguity loop. And if you ask
it something a 100 times, you're not
going to get the same result 100 times.
And then you refuse to let the agent say
it's done. But you have to identify what
the stop condition is. And if the stop
condition is unclear and it's done
anything at all to try to wiggle its way
out, you say no, do it again. Like for
example, all tests must pass. Endpoints
must be working. And then if it comments
a test out and you can't comment, you
can't change the tests or whatever,
right? So you'll say / Ralph loop
refactor this to whatever and it all has
to pass. And you have to go and say step
step and when it's complete, when it's
complete, when it's complete. If it
doesn't have the ability to see
something, if it can't see a log file,
if it can't run a test, then that
doesn't work. So that's why test
harnesses matter so much in that
context.
>> So you're basically building your own
while loop with a known stop condition
that's going to call out to your model
of choice.
>> Yeah. And then you can also mix and
match models. So like I'm on I'm on
copilot. I'll hit /model. I hit enter.
I've got 14 models. So I might, you
know, plan on Opus. And if I want to
save money, I might then do the work on
Sonnet and then I'll have GPT52 codeex
review it just to kind of like mix it
up. You know, diverse teams are a good
thing. So having only one model do it
and then review it. Sometimes you can
get a little bit of sick fancy. It's
nice to get fresh eyes and a way to do
fresh eyes is throw another model at it.
So I can switch models mid-con
conversation. So for your own personal
projects, what does that that bill look
like at the end of the month? Well, so
far I spend 200 on Claude and then I pay
whatever the co-pilot pro plus is and
those are the two that oh and then I
have a subscription to open AAI. So
that's basically it. I mean here's the
thing, right? What do you value your
time at? Right? If you just pick a
number like a $100 an hour and you say
my time's worth $100 an hour, which is a
big number and one magical moment once a
month saves you a hundred bucks an hour.
Like you're like, "Oh my god, yes, I
would do that." It is definitely brought
me more joy than Netflix. [laughter]
And the Netflix is $1.99 or whatever it
is. All it takes is one amazing moment
and you just go, "Oh, wow. That was I
just paid for the whole thing." You know
what I mean? My son just got a climbing
gym membership yesterday with his own
money. He's 18 and it's $90 a month. And
he's like, "Oh man, this sucks. I climb
for two hours. It's $45 an hour." I'm
like, "No, dude. Climb 4 hours a week.
It's $16 an hour. It's five bucks an
hour." And he's like, "Oh." My son, he's
like, "Bro, you're right. I need to
climb more." Like, "Yeah, the more you
use it, like the better, dude." So, like
I'm, you know, what is it here? Copilot
Pro Plus is like 40 bucks and you get
1,500 premium requests and I've used how
many have I used here? Session. I've
used 63, right? I've upgraded Open Live
Writer. It's not even it's not even
close. It's so valuable that it is a
delight. So, I honestly am not I'm not
thinking that much about it simply
because like I said before, I've got a
rocket ship on my back. I'm busting out
so much cool stuff. And people might say
it's a toy. this thing's a toy or that
thing's a toy. But like there are toys
that I was meaning to get to. Like I've
got a podcast as well, you know? It's
been going on for 20 years, but it's
never had a back-end admin site. I just
been editing text files and like
manually editing databases because I was
like, uh, who's got a weekend to make a
P I don't know, make a P. It took me 43
minutes to make a React website that
does the backend admin for my podcast.
That's worth that's worth whatever my
subscription is. So yeah, did not take
any time at all to make that decision.
>> Yeah, I mean I think as developers for
whatever reason a lot of us we
undervalue paying for tools. Oh my god.
Developers would just love like I'm $99.
Never I'll write my own take 9 hours to
do it. You know what I mean? So yeah,
like I mean I'm sure that these these AI
companies are burning money and the
pricing will figure itself out. This is
just like when Netflix and streaming
started and they couldn't figure out
what the pricing is. But they're all
trying to figure it out. And it's also
going to get faster. It's going to get
more environmentally friendly. We'll
have more hybrid models. We'll have more
local models. I can plug in Olama. I've
got a 4080. I could do work on work
locally. There's lots and lots and lots
of options. And it's only going to get
easier and hopefully cheaper. And that's
important as well. I want this to be
available like for everyone.
>> Yeah. One of the things you mentioned is
that there are models you can run
locally. What's the state of that? How
do they compare to the ones that you pay
for from cloud services? It is
challenging to get really good, deep,
thoughtful plans from those local
models. But if you have a good plan that
was made by a big cloud model, you can
then execute on that plan with some of
the smaller ones. I think though that
people don't realize that these models
in the cloud know more than just coding.
They could go and translate Star Wars
into Shakespeare, but I don't want that
feature. Like I don't need that. So when
I download a model, I would like a
Python optimized model that doesn't know
how to do anything but Python. It does.
I don't care. It shouldn't have tall is
Brad Pitt embedded in the model. That's
wasting space. So I think we're going to
see local models that are very specific.
And you can go on Hugging Face and find
llama coding models, deepseat coding
models that are specific programming
languages or problems. That I think
would be really interesting like save
money, time, and energy by solving it
locally. Think of it as like a reddish
cache for LLMs, but locally. I also
wonder
because there's so many things in these
models, how much of that knowledge
actually helps it code because, you
know, we have we have knowledge outside
of coding.
>> They all know how tall Brad Pitt is and
they insist on bringing it with me, you
know, everywhere I go. But a really fun
way to test this is to just go and
download like LM Studio or LM Studio.
It's a delightful application, third
party app or you know foundry local or
lama and then just throw a couple of
problems at it and if you like the
answers then maybe you can do some
coding on an airplane. One thing we
haven't really talked about is these
agents or this Ralph loop. I believe in
a lot of cases it has full access to
your computer. Is that correct?
>> That is 100% up to you. So, for example,
if I were to fire up copilot CLI or
claude in a folder on my machine, if I
just made, you know, C col temp Jeremy
Copilot, it'll say, do I have permission
to open this folder? That's the same
thing that you get when you open it in
Visual Studio Code and it's like, do I
trust this? Are we cool? No. So, that's
preventing it from accessing that that
data. So, there's basically three things
that a agent can do. Can it access a
URL? Can it access a tool? or can it
access a path. So by default it gets no
tools, no paths, no URLs and then every
single time in a session it will ask you
can I do that and it can be very
annoying and you say yeah you know I'm
going to write a you know website for
Jeremy go and uh do this and it'll be
like oh can I can I Google for stuff? Uh
yeah, go ahead fine. Okay, now I have
access to Google. Okay, cool. Can I
write the HTML file to the disk? Is that
cool? And it'll show you what it's about
to write and then you say yes. And then
at some point you'll say, "Well, yeah,
you can just write to the disk for the
rest of the session. We're good. Stop
asking me." And then you build up this
knowledge base of what it's allowed to
do and what it's not allowed to do. What
people are starting to do is they just
go- yolo, you only live once. If you
fire up an agent- yolo or allow all
tools and it's running as admin, it's
running as you. So then you bring in
things like sandboxes. You could use
Windows Sandbox, you could use Docker
sandbox, you could use WSL. A lot of
people are really enjoying WSL on
Windows and then you can unmount the
drive or you can use Docker and use
volume mounting. But simply running it
in a container isn't security. It's a
it's one layer of security. Like a true
sandbox. If you're going to run this
like a bank, you're going to have
auditable governable layers of what it's
allowed to do, what functions, what SIS
calls it can make, etc. So I think we
are in kind of YOLO mode. But no, by
default they do not have access to all
of your stuff. But if you ran it in a
loop in YOLO and went to sleep, like
I've got a 3D printer. Do you have a 3D
printer? Like as a general rule, 3D
printer, people know not to leave the 3D
printer on when they sleep cuz it could
burn your house down. And there's always
somebody that ends up doing that and
they get spaghetti when they come home
and it's just all over the place and it
could, you know, it could cause a
problem. So I don't leave the house when
the printer's going and I don't leave
the house when I have a YOLO Ralph loop
running. But in general, I suppose it
sounds like when you are going to use
these tools, you do put it in yolo mode
and maybe hope for the best.
>> No. Well, if I'm standing in front of it
and I'm actively doing it, usually I'll
say like allow all tools because I know
the tools that it has. I tend to lock
them down by path. So, for example, I'm
in dub
open live writer. It can go ham on
anything from there down. It can talk to
anything on the web and it can talk to
anything from there on that path down
and it can call any tool. I'm sure it
could decide randomly to format my hard
drive, but it's not running as admin. So
that would fail. I suppose it could
randomly have a reason to go out and you
know hit the internet somehow and do
something problematic. But again, it's
working on one specific thing. The loop
that it's doing is looking at a log
file, running a compiler, and doing it
again. That's different than Claudebot
or now called Moltbot which is a
basically Siri as a Ralph loop running
on a you know a server somewhere or
running in a in a in a background
session. But yes, you don't know but
giving it access to like your source
code and having it if it deletes it then
I'll just go and get reset and I'll get
it, you know, I'll get it back. I've had
it do dumb stuff. I've had it push when
I didn't want it to push. I've had it
commit stuff and then I just undo and go
back to running. I always run them in
git. I want to call that out though.
Like I always have source control
because if it makes a mistake, you back
out.
>> Yeah, because I was thinking of the
example you gave earlier where I believe
it was looking at processes and killing
them and things like that.
>> So to me it seems like it must have
quite a bit of permissions if it's able
to do that.
>> Well, so when it runs as you, it has all
the permissions that you have. So, for
example, the loop that I'm running over
on this other machine, I told it that it
can fire up the Windows app, save the
PID of the app that it just ran, and it
can kill that PID. It can kill that
process. That doesn't mean it couldn't
accidentally kill all of the processes.
And I have one time two weeks ago had uh
clawed code kill itself by doing a stop
process and it was a little bit too, you
know, star and then it woke up and it's
like, what happened? How long? It
literally said, how long have I been
out?
>> Wow. [laughter] which I thought was
crazy. It literally was like, "How long
have I been awake?" You know, and I was
like, and I said, "Check the markdown
files, see where you left off and keep
going." And it, you know, it picked it
up, but it basically bonked itself on
the head with its own hammer. And that's
not a guarantee. So then the question
is, is it a sandbox to put in a markdown
file? Hey man, don't do that. No, it's
not. That's obviously not a sandbox. So
that's why running it in a container or,
you know, running it in WSL or whatever,
you know, and that that's non-specific
of any operating system. If you decide
to double click on a batch file and it
does something stupid, I don't see that
as being any different than running an
agent. The only difference is the
ambiguity, which gets us back to the
beginning of the conversation. Ambiguity
loops are ambiguous.
>> Yeah. I mean, I could think of an
example of if you're giving it access to
the internet and maybe it downloads a
utility you think it's going to help.
>> That's a great example. Downloads a
utility that your company hasn't okayed
and then suddenly you're in trouble,
>> right?
>> Yeah. And I think that the difference
between making a toy application that
plays with your blood sugar in your
spare time and working at a bank are
different. So yeah, I would not go
running anything like this, you know, in
YOLO as admin in a bank.
>> Makes sense.
>> That said, if it's your machine and you
know what you're doing and you have this
folder and down, there's a lot of power
in this. And the nice part about it is
that it's a slider bar of good, better,
best. You don't have to say it's not
between bother me all the time and yolo.
You can give it and you can do this as a
team. like the whole enterprise could
roll out. Here are the five approved
tools. Here are the six approved
websites. Here's the skills.mmd that
we're all going to use. We check it all
in with the repo and everyone's on the
same page.
>> I had an interview with Brian Canantrol.
He's the CTO of oxide computer.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I was on ox the oxide and
friends.
>> Oh, nice. And one of the things he he
mentioned with working with large
language models is he thought it was
really advantageous to use strongly
typed languages like say Rust because
the model is able to verify when things
are not correct
>> just through that compile step and
through the design of the language. I
wonder in your impression like whether
you found that true for yourself like
are there specific languages that work
better when using these agents?
>> That is a very good question. I think
that is a good opinion by Brian and as a
general rule I agree with it. But I
would argue that in lie of strong typing
one overcompensates with tests. So
correctness is what Brian is arguing for
and that is valid. If I am using Python
like I am for my blood sugar thing,
having 200 tests make me worry less
about how Python compiles or doesn't.
With my net application, I have fewer
tests, but I've got 419 I'm looking at
this 419,000 lines of code and it all
compiles that. But compilation doesn't
equal correctness and strong typing
doesn't guarantee correctness. So, I
would say I mostly agree with Brian, but
if you go back to fear-driven
development, if you're afraid of the
code, you don't have enough tests. So, I
write tests until I'm no longer afraid,
regardless of language. I would say I am
picking the right language for the
environment, not picking a language
based on whether it's strongly typed or
not.
>> Probably a similar philosophy to when
you're writing the code yourself, even
before these tools,
>> 100%. Although I am finding myself
writing more code in languages that I
don't know because it's the right
language like not everything has to be a
a net application that's like a complete
self-contained crossplatform thing.
Sometimes 100 lines of Python is fine.
Yeah, I think that would be an
interesting shift for people because I I
think there does tend to be people who
they know, let's say they know
JavaScript, so they go, okay, I'm going
to write everything in JavaScript or
Node or TypeScript and maybe this
removes some of the difficulty in
getting started. Let's say Python as an
example. If you're working on something
in the machine learning space, even if
you're not an expert in Python, these
tools can help get you there. Well, like
the blood sugar thing is meant to be a
skill that is plugged into an agent. So,
you put it in C users Jeremy co-pilot
skills or C users Jeremy Claude skills.
So, I did it in Python because it's like
one file, one markdown file and one
Python file. And you have Python and I
have Python. It works. I could have made
it a net application. It would be
larger. It would require a runtime. So,
that wasn't necessary. So, I used Python
for portability. Even though I don't
know Python, I'm confident that it will
work for you and it'll have a good
experience. But, you know, like I might
have I'm trying to think what which one
of these is a net application. Like my
my live rider application, I wouldn't do
it in anything butnet cuz that's what
it's good at. So, pick the car brand
that is going to make your trip the most
delightful. I'm definitely focused on
delight right now.
>> I think that's pretty good place to end
it on, but is there anything else that
you think we should have talked about or
you want to mention? I just think that
it's a funny moment that we're in where
people who are crafts people are worried
that the craft will go away and I hope
that it is just that the toil will go
away, but the craft remains. I am having
a blast. I hope I will be having a blast
this time next year. Maybe we'll chat
and see how it turned out.
>> All right. You mentioned you have a
podcast. You actually have many
podcasts. If people want to check out
what you're up to, where should they
head?
>> Just go to hansselman.com.
hansselman.com. my last name. If there
is a tariff on podcast, I'm afraid I
will have to pay the tariff. I tend to
yap and I apologize for that. But Hansel
Minutes is my podcast. You can get to it
at hsman.com. It's been around over a
thousand episodes over the last 20
years. And then I have a new podcast
with Mark Rinovich, the CTO of Azure,
where we learn something new every week.
It's called Mark and Scott Learn to. So
those are two that people can check out.
>> Yeah, I highly recommend both of those.
It's also amazing how long you've been
doing anel minutes. I think it's been
you said over 20 years, right? Yeah,
it's been a minute. It's been a minute.
Every Thursday for the last thousand
plus episodes. It tries to showcase
faces that you maybe not ordinarily see.
There's like the same three or four
people that do the shows and I'm guilty
of that. But there's a lot of cool
people doing a lot of amazing work. I
recently had a lady who is the IT
manager of the Philadelphia airport and
I learned all about how airports run and
like you don't see folks like that on a
podcast. That's amazing. So yeah,
definitely showcasing people that are
doing great work.
>> Very cool. Well, Scott, thank you so
much for coming on Software Engineering
Radio.
>> Yeah, it's good to see you.
>> This has been Jeremy Jung for Software
Engineering Radio. Thanks for listening.
[music]
>> Thanks for listening to SE Radio, an
educational program brought to you by it
e software magazine. For more about the
podcast, including other episodes, visit
our website at se-radio.net.
To provide feedback, you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter, or
through our Slack channel at seradio.
slack.com. [music]
You can also email us at
teamse-radio.net.
[music] This and all other episodes of
SE Radio is licensed under Creative
Common License 2.5. Thanks for
listening. [music]